Guide to the Arthur and Luce Klein Spoken Arts Records
Yale University Music Library
Arthur and Luce Klein Spoken Arts records
1924-2009
MSS 105
Yale University Music Library
18.35
44 boxes
The collection is comprised of the business records of Spoken Arts, Inc., whose catalog includes covers a wide range of literary works read by 20th century authors, poets, and other notables.
Klein, Arthur Luce
Klein, Luce
Spoken Arts, Inc.
Conditions Governing Access
The collection is open for research.
Biographical / Historical
Founded in 1956 by Dr. Luce and Arthur Klein, Spoken Arts, Inc. was one of the first companies to record the spoken word. The company's first news release clearly stated its mission "to encourage a revival and reevaluation of the importance of the spoken word." In the ensuing years, Spoken Arts became well known for its recordings of 20th century authors and poets reading their own works, including such notables as Arthur Miller, Dorothy Parker, Langston Hughes, Cynthia Ozick, William Butler Yeats, Nadine Gordimer, Pablo Neruda, Gertrude Stein, James Baldwin, Cornelia Otis Skinner, S.J. Perelman, Grace Paley, W. H. Auden, Elie Wiesel, Anais Nin and many others.
The Spoken Arts catalog of over 750 recordings covers a wide range of literature, with subjects from Greek Mythology, Chaucer, Shakespeare, English Literature from the 17th and 18th centuries, English Poetry and Prose from the Romantic and Victorian Ages, Irish Literature, American Classics and Modern Drama, Great Women Writers, Treasuries of Fairy Tales and Folk Tales, Classic Children's Literature, French and Spanish Drama, German Poetry and Prose, Italian Verse, American History and Politics, as well as the Treasury of 100 Modern American poets reading their poems.
See also Spoken Arts Collection, Historical Sound Recordings.
Scope and Contents
The collection is comprised of the business records of Spoken Arts, Inc., whose catalog includes covers a wide range of literary works read by 20th century authors, poets, and other notables.
Arrangement
The collection is arranged into six series: I. Project records, II. Program guides and related materials, III. Promotional materials and miscellanous office records, IV. Artist contracts, V. Artist correspondence and related material, and VI. Records on special projects.
Related Materials
Commercial recordings related to the collection are cataloged in Orbis.
Immediate Source of Acquisition
On July 5th, 2001, Yale University and the Klein Family signed an agreement to establish the Klein Archive as part of the University's Historical Sound Recordings (HSR) Collection.
Business records; Spoken word poetry; Klein, Arthur Luce; Klein, Luce; Spoken Arts, Inc.
- Project records, Series I
  Arrangement
  Series is arranged numerically by Mini-kit, PCC, then SA number.
  - Mini-libraries/kits, 1969–1972 (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Minis: Spoken Arts Cassette Mini-library, 1969–1972 (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Mini-kit 1: Folk and Fairy Tales for Children, undated (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Mini-kit 2: Children's Stories and Rhymes (vol. I), undated (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Mini-kit 3: Children's Stories and Rhymes (vol. II), circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Mini-kit 4: Tales from Across the Ocean, undated (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Mini-kit 5: The Listening Book, undated (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Mini-kit 6: Adventures and Fables, circa 1971 (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Mini-kit 7: Classical Literature, 1971–1973 (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Mini-kit 8: Shakespeare's Tradegies, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Mini-kit 9: Shakespeare's Romantic Comedies, 1971–1973 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Mini-kit 10: Shakespeare's Romances and Chronicle Plays
    - Folder 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 12)
    - Folder 2, 1969–1973 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Mini-kit 11: A Shakespeare Library
    - Folder 1, undated (Box 2, Folder 14)
    - Folder 2, 1969–1973 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Mini-kit 12: English Literature in the 17th Century, 1969–1971 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Mini-kit 13: English Literature in the 18th Century, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Mini-kit 14: English Literature in the Romantic Age, 1969–1971 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Mini-kit 15: English Literature in the Victorian Age, 1969 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Mini-kit 16: American Literature in the Early National Period, 1973 (Box 2, Folder 20)
  - Mini-kit 17: America's Golden Age, undated (Box 2, Folder 21)
  - Mini-kit 18: Mark Twain, 1969–1978 (Box 2, Folder 22)
  - Mini-kit 19: American Literature in Transition, 1969–1971 (Box 2, Folder 23)
  - Mini-kit 20: Twentieth Century Poets (vol. I), 1969–1974 (Box 2, Folder 24)
  - Mini-kit 21: Drama I, 1969–1972 (Box 3, Folder 25)
  - Mini-kit 22: Drama II, 1969 (Box 3, Folder 26)
  - Mini-kit 23: Black America Speaks (vol. I), 1971 (Box 3, Folder 27)
  - Mini-kit 26: Poetry, undated (Box 3, Folder 28)
  - Mini-kit 28: Children of Courage, undated (Box 3, Folder 29)
  - Mini-kit 29: Tales from Distant Lands - Part 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 30)
  - Mini-kit 30: Tales from Distant Lands - Part 2, 1971 (Box 3, Folder 31)
  - Mini-kit 31: Adventure! - Part 1, undated (Box 3, Folder 32)
  - Mini-kit 32: Adventure! - Part 2, undated (Box 3, Folder 33)
  - Mini-kit 33: Wishes, Lies, and Dreams, 1972–1977 (Box 3, Folder 34)
  - Mini-kit 34: Tales of Mystery and Terror, 1972–1978 (Box 3, Folder 35)
  - Mini-kit 35: American Folk Songs and Stories - Part 1, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 36)
  - Mini-kit 36: American Folk Songs and Stories - Part 2, 1972 (Box 3, Folder 37)
  - Mini-kit 37: Favorite Classical Stories, undated (Box 3, Folder 38)
  - Mini-kit 38: Modern and Classical Stories for Children (Part I), 1972 (Box 3, Folder 39)
  - Mini-kit 39: Modern and Classical Stories for Children (Part II), undated (Box 4, Folder 40)
  - Mini-kit 40: Classic American Short Stories, 1972 (Box 4, Folder 41)
  - Mini-kit 41: John Ciardi Collection, undated (Box 4, Folder 42)
  - Mini-kit 33-41, undated (Box 4, Folder 43)
    Scope and Contents
    Label copies.
  - Mini-kit 42: London, Jack, 1973–1974 (Box 4, Folder 44)
  - Mini-kit 43: Twentieth Century Novelists, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 45)
  - Mini-kit 43-50, 1974–1978 (Box 4, Folder 48)
    43 - Twentieth Century Novelists; 44 - Distinguished Women Writers; 45 - Treasury of Irish Literature - Part 1; 46 - Treasury of Irish Literature - Part 2; 47 - French: Songs, Idioms, Dictations, Conversations, Stories; 48 - French Literature: Poetry, Prose, Drama; 49 - Spanish Literature: Songs, Dictados, Verse, Prose, Drama (vol. I); 50 - Spanish Literature: Dictados, Verse, Prose, Drama (vol. II).
  - Mini-kit 44: Distinguished Women Writers, 1978 (Box 4, Folder 46)
  - Mini-kit 45: Treasury of Irish Literature - Part 1, undated (Box 4, Folder 47)
  - Mini-kit 51: Poe, Edgar Allan, 1975 (Box 4, Folder 49)
  - Mini-kit SAC 52: An American Crisis, 1973–1984 (Box 4, Folder 50)
  - SAC 5000: Mini-kits 53-56, 1977, 1982 (Box 4, Folder 51)
    53 - From Revol.ution to Civil War; 54 - Westward Ho; 55 - Building America; 56 - America Comes of Age.
  - Mini-kit 57: French Literature II, 1977–1978 (Box 4, Folder 52)
    Moliere, Maupassant, La Fontaine.
  - PCC 65: Saurraute, Nathalie, 1983–1986 (Box 4, Folder 53)
  - PCC 71: The Secret Garden, 1986–1987 (Box 5, Folder 54)
  - PCC 74-75: Grey, Zane, 1986–1987 (Box 5, Folder 55)
  - PCC 79: Production Folder, undated (Box 5, Folder 56)
  - SA 101: Psychology of Sexual Relations, 1966 (Box 5, Folder 57)
  - SA 201
    - Mahler - Invitation to Music, N8-OP-8794-8795, 1959–1967 (Box 5, Folder 58)
      Includes photographs.
    - Fritz Mahler Contract, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 59)
  - SA 202-1: Prichard, Dr. Robert - Pianist, N8-OP-8770-8771
    - Folder 1, 1962 (Box 5, Folder 60)
    - Folder 2, 1962–1965 (Box 5, Folder 61)
  - SA 203: "Silver Swords" Steel Band, St. Thomas, Virgin Islands, N8-OP-8796-8797, 1953-1962, 1975 (Box 5, Folder 62)
  - SA 204: Dermot O'Brien and Music of Ireland, 1962, 1986 (Box 5, Folder 63)
  - SA 205: Chang, Mrs. W., Chinese Songs
    - Folder 1, 1962–1964 (Box 5, Folder 64)
    - Folder 2, production, 1962–1963 (Box 5, Folder 65)
  - SA 206: Eigeartaigh, Grainne Ni, Irish and Gaelic Songs, 1962–1986 (Box 5, Folder 66)
  - SA 207: Purcell,Henry: Complete Keyboard Works, NO-8P-3776-3777, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 67)
  - SA 208: Purcell, Henry: Complete Keyboard Works, NO-8P-3778-3779, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 68)
  - SA 209: Purcell, Henry: 12 Sonatas in three parts, NO-8P-3780-3781, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 69)
  - SA 210: Purcell, Henry: 12 Sonatas in three parts, NO-8P-3782-3783, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 70)
  - Sa 211: Carington Men's Chours
    - Folder 1, NO-8P-6229-6230, 1962–1965 (Box 6, Folder 71)
    - Folder 2, royalty, 1962 (Box 6, Folder 72)
  - SA 213: Chansons de la Vieille France, 1963, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 73)
  - SA 214, SA215: Gaussens, circa 1964, 1986-1987 (Box 6, Folder 74)
  - SA 216: Brendan Mulhaire's Ceili Band, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 75)
  - SA 217: McCann: Michael, 1964, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 76)
  - SA 218: Dermot O'Brien and His Ceili Band, 1964 (Box 6, Folder 77)
  - SA 219: Greevy: Bernadette, 1964–1986 (Box 6, Folder 78)
  - SA 220: McCaffrey: Phillip, 1966-1974, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 79)
    Includes Photographs and slides.
  - SA 221: Christmas in Kilkenny, 1966, 1977, 1986 (Box 6, Folder 80)
  - SA223
    - Folder 1, Child's Introduction to American Folksongs, 1970–1987 (Box 6, Folder 81)
    - Folder 2, Ed McCurdy series, undated (Box 6, Folder 82)
  - SA 224: Spoken Arts Introduction to American Folk Songs, 1970, 1987 (Box 6, Folder 83)
  - SA 701: Golden Treasury of German Verse, Schnitzler, 1974-1978, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 84)
  - SA 702: Slosson, Professor Preston, XTV 24448-49, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 85)
  - SA 703: Baxter, Dr. Frank C., N8-OP-9641-42, 1961 (Box 7, Folder 86)
  - SA 704: America's Great Playwrights: Arthur Miller
    - Folder 1, 1962 (Box 7, Folder 87)
    - Folder 2, LO8P-2644-45, 1956–1966 (Box 7, Folder 88)
  - SA 705: Perlman, S. J., 1976 (Box 7, Folder 89)
  - SA 706: The Golden Treasury of Irish Verse, Colum, Padraic, 1961, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 90)
  - SA 710: Betjeman, John
    - Folder 1, John Murray - Hilda Radford (L8-OP-8714-8715), 1956-1961, 1972 (Box 7, Folder 91)
    - Folder 2, Golden Treasury of John Betjeman, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 92)
  - SA 711: French Verse - Vilar, Jean, HO-8P-1101-1102, 1960-1961, 1973 (Box 7, Folder 93)
  - SA 712: Golden Treasury of Catholic Verse, M80P-0380-81, 1956, 1961, 1983 (Box 7, Folder 94)
  - SA 713: Barzun, Jacques, XTV 24658-59, 1960, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 95)
  - SA 714: Hutchins, Robert, MO-8P-3438-39, undated (Box 7, Folder 96)
  - SA 715: Golden Treasury of French Drama, LO-8P-2646-47, 1960–1961 (Box 7, Folder 97)
  - SA 716: An Informal Hour With J. B. Priestly, 1977 (Box 7, Folder 98)
  - SA 717: Blitzstein, Mark, PR-4M-6130-31, undated (Box 7, Folder 99)
  - SA 718: van Druten, John
    - Folder 1, SK-4M-1664-6, 1957, 1965 (Box 7, Folder 100)
    - Folder 2, XTV-25049-50, 1960 (Box 7, Folder 101)
  - SA 720: Irish Fairy Tales, HO-8P-1103-04, 1960, 1975 (Box 7, Folder 102)
  - SA 721: An Informal Hour with Erskine Caldwell, PR-4M-4009-4010, 1976 (Box 7, Folder 103)
  - SA 722: Dobie, J. Frank, XTV-25051-52, 1956-1962, 1986 (Box 7, Folder 104)
  - SA 723, SA836, SA837: Production File - Shakespeare
    - Folder 1, 1959, undated (Box 7, Folder 105)
      Includes two sets of slides.
    - Folder 2, undated (Box 7, Folder 106)
  - SA 724: Oscar Wilde read by Pettingell, XTV 25055-56, 1965–1966 (Box 7, Folder 107)
  - SA 725: Hart, Moss, XTV-25059-60, 1959-1963, 1975 (Box 8, Folder 108)
  - SA 726: Production File - Dorothy Parker, 1961, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 109)
  - SA 728: Production File - A Christmas Carol, 1960–1972 (Box 8, Folder 110)
  - SA 729: Shakespeare Sonnets - Quayle, 1960, 1966, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 111)
  - SA 732: Piccoli, HO-8P-1105-06, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 112)
  - SA 734: Poems of T. S. Eliot, 1960 (Box 8, Folder 113)
  - SA 735: Teller, Edward
    - Folder 1, 1976, 1985 (Box 8, Folder 114)
    - Folder 2, H8-OP-8240-41, 1957-1960, 1976 (Box 8, Folder 115)
  - SA 741: Dickens Duets - Pettingell, Frank, 1957–1960 (Box 8, Folder 116)
  - SA 742: The Midnight Court, J8OP-0134-35, 1957–1958 (Box 8, Folder 117)
  - SA 743: Riders to the Sea - In the Shadow of the Glen, J8OP-0136-37, 1955-1958, 1974 (Box 8, Folder 118)
  - SA 744: Stephens, James, 1983 (Box 8, Folder 119)
  - SA 745: Ann Moray Presents Gaelic Songs and Legends, 1957–1986 (Box 8, Folder 120)
  - SA 746: Marshall, Lenore G. - Contract, 1957-1960, 1967 (Box 8, Folder 121)
  - SA 747: Wilbur, Richard - Poems and Contract, 1957-1959, 1976, 1987 (Box 8, Folder 122)
  - SA 748: Klein, Arthur Luce, 1981 (Box 8, Folder 123)
  - SA 750: Rusch, Dr. P. - The World of Science, K8-OP-1796-97
    - 1 of 2, 1958–1959 (Box 8, Folder 124)
    - 2 of 2, 1958–1959 (Box 8, Folder 125)
  - SA 751: Yeats, William Butler - Poems and Memories, 1974, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 126)
  - SA 752: Yeats - Plays and Memories by Lennox Robinson, JO8P-2810-11, 1956-1957, 1966 (Box 9, Folder 127)
  - SA 753: Yeats, William Butler
    - Yeats, Mr William Butler, 1957-1959, 1983 (Box 9, Folder 128)
    - The Poems of W.B. Yeats - by Yeats, J8-OP-1044-45, 1960, 1974-1987 (Box 9, Folder 129)
  - SA 754: Burns, Robert
    - Burns, Robert, 1986–1987 (Box 9, Folder 130)
      Includes negative.
  - Love Songs of Robert Burns by Ann Moray, K8-OP-1798-99, 1957–1961
    - 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 131)
    - 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 132)
    - Burns, Robert, 1958–1959 (Box 9, Folder 133)
  - SA755: Story of Ossian by John Masefield - Academy of American Poets, K8-OP-3839-40, 1958–1960
    - 1 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 134)
    - 2 of 2 (Box 9, Folder 135)
  - SA756: Pasternak Poems, K8-OP-3735-36, 1959-1961, 1986 (Box 9, Folder 136)
  - SA757: Eban, Abba
    - Folder 1, Abba Eban Speeches, 1965–1968 (Box 9, Folder 137)
    - Folder 2, Eban, Abba, 1986–1987 (Box 9, Folder 138)
    - American Friends of Jerusalem, 1959–1961 (Box 9, Folder 139)
    - Eban, Abba, 1957–1970 (Box 10, Folder 140)
    - Abba Eban Reads Psalms and Eccleasiates, ISBN 0-8045-0757-0, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 141)
    - Eban, Abba, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 142)
  - SA758, SA765: Elliot, T. S. - Practical Cats (SA758) and Four Quartets (SA765), 1959–1961 (Box 10, Folder 143)
  - SA759
    - Folder 1, Thomas, Norman, 1959-1964, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 144)
    - Folder 2, Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 10, Folder 145)
  - SA761: Poems of Emily Dickinson, L8-OP-0624-25, 1959-1960, 1976 (Box 10, Folder 146)
    Read by Nancy Wickwire.
  - SA762: Emlyn Williams as Charles Dickens, KO-8P-2771-72, 1959 (Box 10, Folder 147)
  - SA763: O'Doherty: Brian - Museum of Fine Arts, 1959–1967 (Box 10, Folder 148)
  - SA764: Vega, Editions Seghers - "Poems of Today" contract, 1958–1986 (Box 10, Folder 149)
  - SA768: Golden Treasury of Milton - Keats, Shelly, L8-OP-3103-04, 1959–1968 (Box 10, Folder 150)
    Read by Hilton Edwards.
  - SA769: Stories from Irish Fireside, 1960–1966 (Box 10, Folder 151)
    Told by Eamon Kelly.
  - SA770: Portrait of Adlai Stevenson in Conversation with Arnold Michaelis, L8-OP-3086-87, 1960–1967 (Box 10, Folder 152)
  - SA771: Golden Treasury of Italian Verse
    - L8-OP-3109-3110, 1960, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 153)
    - Texts and Translations, undated (Box 11, Folder 154)
    - Read by Giorgio Strehler, L8-OP-3107-08, circa 1960, 1977-1978 (Box 11, Folder 155)
  - SA771: Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 11, Folder 156)
  - SA772: Golden Treasury of AmerIcan Verse, L8-OP-3109-10, 1960, 1974 (Box 11, Folder 157)
    Read by Alexander Scourby and Nancy Wickwire.
  - SA773, SA774: Invitation to Hebrew - Kamrat, Dr Modecai, undated (Box 11, Folder 158)
  - SA775: The Conquest of Space - Laurence, William L., L8-OP-8716-17, 1960–1961
    - Folder 1 (Box 11, Folder 159)
      Includes contract, correspondence, and photographs.
    - Folder 2 (Box 11, Folder 160)
      Text.
  - SA776: The Psalms - Carnovsky, Morris, 1957–1977 (Box 11, Folder 161)
  - SA777: The Song of Songs, L8-OP-8869-70, 1960–1961 (Box 11, Folder 162)
    Read by Carol Veazie and Morris Carnovsky. Includes photographs.
  - SA778: Mark Twain, L8-OP-8708-09, 1958-1965, 1985 (Box 11, Folder 163)
    Read by Hiram Sherman.
  - SA779: Draper, Ruth (vol. 1), L8-OP-3113-14, 1960–1985 (Box 12, Folder 164)
  - SA785: Oscar Wilde Fairy Tales: The Happy Prince and The Remarkable Rocket, 1960 (Box 12, Folder 165)
  - SA786: Georges Courteline, 1960-1961, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 166)
    Directed by John Blatchley.
  - SA787: Contes de Perrault, LO-8P-2554-55, 1960, 1974 (Box 12, Folder 167)
  - SA788: Krapp's Last Tape, LO-8P-2623-24, 1960-1961, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 168)
  - SA790: The Rime of the Ancient Mariner, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 169)
  - SA791, SA792: Under Milk Wood, M8-OP-0449-52 (SA791), M8-OP-0450-51 (SA792), 1961 (Box 12, Folder 170)
  - SA793, SA794: Comedie de Moliere, 1960–1961 (Box 12, Folder 171)
  - SA795, SA796, SA797: Golden Treasury of French Prose, 1960-1961, 1983 (Box 12, Folder 172)
    Riquier and Le Marchand.
  - SA798: Draper, Ruth (vol. 2), F2-RP-4574-75, 1960–1961 (Box 12, Folder 173)
  - SA799: Draper, Ruth (vol. 3), F2-RP-4570-71, 1960, 1975 (Box 12, Folder 174)
  - SA800: Draper, Ruth (vol. 4), F2-RP-4572-73, R2-RP-4568-69, 1960–1961 (Box 12, Folder 175)
  - SA801: Golden Treasury of Apollianaire, Cocteau, Eluard and Aragon, N8-Op 3847-48, 1960-1962, 1987 (Box 12, Folder 176)
  - SA802, SA803: French Dictees, 1960–1986 (Box 12, Folder 177)
    Read by Prof. Jean Gabriel Gaussen.
  - SA803: Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 12, Folder 178)
  - SA804: The Poems of Stephen Spender, M8-OP-0518-19, 1961 (Box 12, Folder 179)
  - SA805: Draper, Ruth (vol. 5), M7-OP-0121, M7-OP-0576, 1961, 1980-1983 (Box 12, Folder 180)
  - SA806, SA807: Basler, Dr Roy P. - Lincoln's Speeches, 1959–1961 (Box 12, Folder 181)
  - SA808: "The Zoo Story" by Edward Albee, 1961, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 182)
  - SA810: Merchant of Venice, 1961, undated (Box 13, Folder 183)
    Julius Cesar pamphlet enclosed.
  - SA810: Plus various other SA numbers, 1968 (Box 13, Folder 184)
    Includes Mrs. Toby Lelyveld correspondence.
  - SA811: Schnitzler: Henry - German Prose Drama, 1960–1986 (Box 13, Folder 185)
  - SA813: Skinner, Cornelia Otis, NO-8P-1134-35, 1962–1963 (Box 13, Folder 186)
  - SA814: Speaight: Robert - Blake: Hopkins, 1961 (Box 13, Folder 187)
  - SA818: Love Poems of Lawrence Durrell, 1961-1962, 1983 (Box 13, Folder 188)
  - SA820: Treasury of Verse for Children, 1961, 1974 (Box 13, Folder 189)
    Read by Robert Speaight and Jill Bacon.
  - SA822: Golden Treasury of French Literature, N8-OP-3849-50, 1961–1987 (Box 13, Folder 190)
  - SA822: Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 13, Folder 191)
  - SA823: Just So Stories, 1961, 1974-1978 (Box 13, Folder 192)
    Read by Balcon and Speaight.
  - SA825, SA826, SA827: Inaugural addresses, 1962, 1964 (Box 13, Folder 193)
    Production.
  - SA825, SA826, SA827: Inaugural Addresses of Presidents Roosevelt, Truman, Eisenhower, and Kennedy, 1961, 1967 (Box 13, Folder 194)
  - SA828: Redgrave reads Chekhov, N8-OP-5420-21, 1961-1962, 1985 (Box 13, Folder 195)
  - SA829: Golden Treasury of Spanish Verse, N8-OP-5422-23
    - Folder 1, 1960–1983 (Box 13, Folder 196)
    - Folder 2, 1961–1963 (Box 14, Folder 197)
  - SA830: The Pit and the Pendulum by Poe, N8-OP-5424-25, 1962, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 198)
    Read by Scourby.
  - SA830: Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 199)
  - SA831: Golden Treasury of Spanish Prose
    - Folder 1, 1962-1963. 1987 (Box 14, Folder 200)
      Read by Manuel Duran. Includes photographs.
    - Folder 2, undated (Box 14, Folder 201)
  - SA832: Walden by Thoreau, 1962–1985 (Box 14, Folder 202)
    Read by Howard Mumford Jones. Includes photographs.
  - SA832: Plus various other SA numbers, 1985 (Box 14, Folder 203)
  - SA833: Iliad-Odyssey, N8-OP-6378-79, 1962–1967 (Box 14, Folder 204)
    Translated and Read by Ennis Rees.
  - SA834: Robinson, Dr Kenneth - Books and the Bad Life, N8-OP-6380-81, 1962–1963
    - 1 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 205)
    - 2 of 2 (Box 14, Folder 206)
  - SA835: Ciardi, John, 1962-1965, 1968 (Box 14, Folder 207)
  - SA836: Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 208)
  - SA837: Plus various other SA numbers, 1986 (Box 14, Folder 209)
  - SA838: French Songs for Children, N8-OW 8726-27, 1962, 1975 (Box 14, Folder 210)
  - SA839: Golden Treasury of Spanish-American Verse, N8-OP-8768-69, 1962, 1965 (Box 15, Folder 211)
  - SA839: Golden Treasury of Spanish-American Poetry, 1962, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 212)
    Read by Manuel Duran.
  - SA840: Grimm's Fairy Tales, N8-OP-8895-96, 1962-1963, 1970 (Box 15, Folder 213)
  - SA840: Plus various other SA numbers, 1984–1985 (Box 15, Folder 214)
  - SA841: Scenes de la Vie Francaise, N8-OP-8915-16, 1961–1962 (Box 15, Folder 215)
  - SA842: Emerson, R.W., 1962–1963 (Box 15, Folder 216)
  - SA843: Vega, Lope de - Los Melindres de Belisa, N8-OP-9145-46, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 217)
  - SA844: La Fiera Domida, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 218)
  - SA845: Grimm's Fairy Tales, NO-8P-0968-69, 1962–1963 (Box 15, Folder 219)
  - SA846: Grimm's Fairy Tales, NO-8P-0970-71, 1962 (Box 15, Folder 220)
  - SA847: Best Loved Fairy Tales, NO-8P-0972-73, 1962–1984 (Box 15, Folder 221)
  - SA848: Donat, Robert, NO-8P-1136-37, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 222)
  - SAC848, SAC849: Iliad and Odyssey, 1986–1987 (Box 15, Folder 223)
  - SA849: Robert Speaight reads the poems of Goldsmith, Gray, Collins, 1963 (Box 15, Folder 224)
  - SA850: Melville, Herman - Moby Dick, NO-8P-3619-20, 1961–1987 (Box 15, Folder 225)
    Read by Robert H. Chapman.
  - SA851: Manana de Sol - Selections of Spanish Literature, NO-8P-3709-10, 1962, 1987 (Box 15, Folder 226)
  - SA852-SA853: Spanish Dictations (Duran, Manuel)
    - Folder 1, 1962-1963, 1983 (Box 15, Folder 227)
    - Folder 2, 1963, 1975 (Box 15, Folder 228)
  - SA852-SA902: Press notices, 1964, 1968 (Box 15, Folder 229)
  - SA854: Finnegan's Wake, P4-RM-2435-36, 1962-1963, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 230)
    Read by Patrick Bedford.
  - SA855: Bowles, Paul - The Delicate Prey and A Distant Episode, P4-RM-2106-07, 1963, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 231)
  - SA856: Gulliver's Travels - Johnston, Denis, 1964, 1983 (Box 16, Folder 232)
  - SA857: Treasury of Nursery Rhymes (vol. I) - Casson, Christopher, P4-RM-2437-38, 1962-1963, 1971 (Box 16, Folder 233)
  - SA858: Treasury of Tennyson, 1986, undated (Box 16, Folder 234)
    Read by Robert Speaight.
  - SA859: Treasury of John Donne, 1983, undated (Box 16, Folder 235)
  - SA860: Treasury of William Woodsworth, 1965, 1967 (Box 16, Folder 236)
  - SA861: Treasury of Robert Browning, 1964 (Box 16, Folder 237)
  - SA862: Golden Treasury of Spanish Drama (vol. I), 1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 238)
  - SA862, SA863, SA864, SA865: Treasury of Spanish Drama (vols. I-III) (SA862-864) - Spanish Songs for Children (SA865), 1962–1963 (Box 16, Folder 239)
  - SA863: Golden Treasury of Spanish Drama (vol. II), 1975-1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 240)
  - SA864: Golden Treasury of Spanish Drama (vol. III), 1987, undated (Box 16, Folder 241)
  - SA865: Spanish Songs for Children, 1963, 1978 (Box 16, Folder 242)
  - SA866: Treasury of John Dryden, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 243)
  - SA867: Treasury of John Milton, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 244)
    Read by Speaight and Eddison.
  - SA868: Treasury of John Keats, 1963 (Box 16, Folder 245)
  - SA869: Treasury of Shelley, 1963, 1974 (Box 16, Folder 246)
  - SA870: A Man's a Man - Brecht, Bertolt, 1963–1968 (Box 16, Folder 247)
    Adapted by Eric Bentley.
  - SA871: Hans Christian Anderson (vol. I), 1963, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 248)
  - SA871-SA877: Hans Christian Andersen, Christopher Casson and Eve Watkins, 1962–1963 (Box 17, Folder 249)
  - SA872: Hans Christian Andersen (vol. II), 1963, 1985 (Box 17, Folder 250)